Guide to the Ray DiPalma Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Ray DiPalma Papers
1966-2002
YCAL MSS 776
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
38.17
(46 boxes) + 7 broadside folders
Collections consists of correspondence, writings, printed material, artwork, photographs, audiovisual material, computer media, and personal papers by and relating to American poet and visual artist Ray DiPalma.
DiPalma, Ray
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Granary Books, Inc. on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund, 2005. Additional material purchased from Ray DiPalma on the George B. Alvord Fund, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 39-40 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 51 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Ray DiPalma (1943-)
Ray DiPalma, American poet and visual artist, was born in New Kensington, Pennsylvania and educated at Duquesne University (1966) and the University of Iowa (1968). DiPalma has published over 30 books of poetry, translations, and graphic work, including the recent House of Keys (2010), The Ancient Use of Stone: Journals and Daybooks 1998-2008 (2009), Pensieri (2009), and Further Apocrypha (2009). Earlier collections include Numbers and Tempers: Selected Early Poems, 1966-1986 (1993), Le Tombeau de Reverdy (1997), Provocations (1994), Hôtel des Ruines (1993), and Planh (1979). His visual work has been collected by galleries and museums, including the J. Paul Getty Museum, the Museum of Modern Art (MoMA), and the Art Institute of Chicago. He has received awards and fellowships from the National Endowment for the Arts, the New York Foundation for the Arts, and the Fund for Poetry. DiPalma lives in New York City and teaches at the School of Visual Arts.
Biographical information taken from The Poetry Foundation website at <http://www.poetryfoundation.org/bio/ray-dipalma>.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, printed material, artwork, photographs, audiovisual material, computer media, and personal papers by and relating to American poet and visual artist Ray DiPalma. Correspondence includes large files for Vincent Dussol, DiPalma's French translator, American poets Merrill Gilfillan, Ken McCullough, Ron Silliman, and Paul Vangelisti, Mail Art, and smaller files for other authors and visual artists chiefly of DiPalma's generation. These correspondents include Bruce Andrews, Charles Bernstein, Guy Davenport, Lyn Hejinian, Peter Klappert, Michael Lally, and Tom Raworth. DiPalma's literary and artistic output includes drafts, proofs, and printed versions of written work and representations of graphic work dating from the mid 1960s. Supplementing this professional output are printed materials, including clippings and publicity, and sound recordings of readings. Also found in the collection are various personal papers, including diaries, notebooks, journals, and calenders.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: June 2005 Acquisition and July 2006 Acquisition.
American literature -- 20th Century; Mail art; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Electronic documents; Photographic prints; Sound recordings; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Andrews, Bruce, 1948-; Bernstein, Charles, 1950-; Davenport, Guy, 1927-2005; DiPalma, Ray; Dussol, Vincent; Gilfillan, Merrill, 1945-; Hejinian, Lyn; Klappert, Peter, 1942-; Lally, Michael, 1942-; McCullough, Ken, 1943-; Raworth, Tom, 1938-; Silliman, Ronald, 1946-; Vangelisti, Paul, 1945-
- June 2005 Acquisition, 1960-2005; 37.97; (45 boxes) + 7 broadside folders
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 39 (reel-to-reel tapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 40 (audiocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 51 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Arrangement
  Organized into eight groupings: Correspondence, Writings and Other Papers, Artists' Books, Graphic Works, Personal Papers, Printed Material, Miscellaneous Material, and Audiovisual Material.
  Scope and Contents
  The June 2005 Acquisition consists of correspondence, writings, printed material, artwork, photographs, audiovisual material, computer media, and personal papers.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 796.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Granary Books, Inc. on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund, 2005.
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming Correspondence
      - Joa o Almino, 1994-1996, undated (Box 1)
      - Andrews, Bruce, 1973-1979, undated; 3 (Box 1)
      - Andersson, May; Delay, Alexandre, 1992-2000, undated; 11 (Box 1)
      - Ashbery, John; Guest, Barbara; Phillips, Dennis; Bennett, Guy; Albiach, Anne-Marie; Shoptaw, John; Swenson, Cole; et al., 1992-2001, undated; 4 (Box 1)
      - Baltaus, Fritz, circa 1982 (Box 1)
      - Benveniste, Asa, 1971-1977 (Box 1)
      - Bertrand, Aloysius "30 Poems from Gaspard Nuit", undated (Box 1)
      - Bernstein, Charles, 1970-1992, undated (Box 1)
      - Bonvicino, Regis, 1996 February 25 (Box 1)
      - Brodey, Kim, 1976, undated (Box 1)
      - Brandfass, Elizabeth, 1970-1971; 9 (Box 2)
      - Card, Macgregor, 1999 February 16 (Box 2)
      - Centre International de Poesie Marseille, 2005 (Box 2)
      - Chax Press, 2000; 2 (Box 2)
      - Clifford, Wayne, 1979 (Box 2)
      - Cole, Norma, 1993 September (Box 2)
      - Creely, Robert, 1990-1995 (Box 2)
      - Davenport, Guy, 1975-1990, undated; 2 (Box 2)
      - Delay, Alexandre, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
      - Dussol, Vincent, 1999-2005; 8 (Box 2)
      - Dussol, Vincent, 2004-2005; 5 (Box 3)
      - Dussol, Vincent, 2000-2004; 14 (Box 4)
      - Evans, Nancy, 2004-2005 (Box 4)
      - Favre, Celine, circa 2005 (Box 4)
      - Frangione, Nicola, undated
      - Gilfillan, Merrill, 1991-2004, undated; 5 (Box 4)
      - Gilfillan, Merrill, 1969-2004; 11 (Box 5)
      - Girard, Eric, 1998-2000, undated (Box 5)
      - Gottlieb, Michael, undated (Box 5)
      - Gray, Darrell, 1969-1984; 2 (Box 5)
      - Groat, Gary, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
      - Greenwald, Ted, circa 1972 (Box 5)
      - Hejinian, Lyn, 1972-1995, undated; 3 (Box 5)
      - Hewitt; Winch; Bergland, 1969-1987, undated (Box 6)
      - Emmanuel Hocquard; Juliette Valery, 1993-2002 (Box 6)
      - Johnson, Ronald, 1989-1990, undated (Box 6)
      - Klappert, Peter, 1997-2001, undated; 2 (Box 6)
      - Lally, Michael, 1967-2002, undated; 5 (Box 6)
      - "Legend", 1976-1979, undated; 6 (Box 6)
      - MacLow, Jackson, 1988-1995, undated; 2 (Box 6)
      - Magee, Michael, 1998-2001 (Box 6)
      - Mail Art correspondence, 1970-2000, undated; 6 (Box 6)
      - McCaffery, Steve, 1976-1996 (Box 7)
      - McCullough, Ken, 1970-2005, undated; 15 (Box 7)
      - Messerli, Douglas; Watten, Barrett, 1975-1990 (Box 7)
      - MFA applicants, 1972-1983, undated (Box 7)
      - Musee d'Art Modern de la Ville de Paris, 1986 June 30 (Box 7)
      - Mohr, Bill, 2001-2003 (Box 7)
      - Orange, Tom, 2000 (Box 7)
      - Otis College of Art and Design, 2005 May 9 (Box 7)
      - Palmer, [Williams], 1967-1988, undated (Box 7)
      - Partisan Review, 1980-2003, undated (Box 7)
      - Raworth, Tom, 1970-2004, undated; 2 (Box 7)
      - Ron, Martha, undated (Box 8)
      - Royet-Journoud, Claude, 1986-2004, undated; 7 (Box 8)
      - Shoptaw, 1998-2001 (Box 8)
      - Sherry, James, undated (Box 8)
      - Schaefer, Stan, 1998-2001 (Box 8)
      - Shrader, Steve, 1969-1970, undated; 2 (Box 8)
      - Silliman, Ron, 1971-1990, undated; 4 (Box 8)
      - Silliman, Ron, undated (Box 8)
        Contains "Wet Loom Star"
      - Silliman, Ron, 1971-1993, undated; 3 (Box 8)
      - Starbuck, George, 1968-1969, undated (Box 8)
      - Sullivan, Gary, 1997 March (Box 8)
      - Sun & Moon Press, 1993, undated (Box 8)
      - Swenson, Cole, 1993, undated (Box 8)
      - The Tele-Monitor Co., Inc., 1996 October 3 (Box 8)
      - Valery, Juliette, 1990-2001, undated (Box 8)
      - Vangelisti, [Paul?], 1996-2003, undated; 8 (Box 9)
      - Waldrop, 1971-1977 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1974-2000, undated; 11 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1998-2002; 4 (Box 10)
      - Unidentified, 1999, undated (Box 10)
      - Unsorted, 1964-2004, undated; 13 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous, 1991-2001; 9 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous, 1960-2005, undated; 32 (Box 11)
      - Unsorted, 1977-1988, undated; 2 (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous, 1969-2001, undated; 24 (Box 12)
      - Unsorted, 1998-2001, undated (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous, 1981-2004, undated; 7 (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous, undated; 2 (Box 13)
    - Outgoing Correspondence
      - Letters: March 12, 1990 - February 28, 1991, 1989-1991 (Box 14)
      - Letters: March 4, 1991 - May 29, 1991 (Box 14)
      - Letters: June 3, 1991 - December 20, 1991 (Box 14)
      - Letters: 1992 (Box 14)
      - Letters: 1993, 2 (Box 14)
      - Letters: January - April 1994 (Box 14)
      - Letters: May 2, 1994 - August 31, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Letters: September 1 - December 30, 1994 (Box 14)
      - Letters: January 3, 1995 - April 25, 1995 (Box 14)
      - Letters: May 1, 1995 - August 31, 1995 (Box 14)
      - Letters: September 5, 1995 - December 29, 1995 (Box 14)
      - Letters: January 3 - March 31, 1996 (Box 14)
      - Letters: April 3, 1996 - July 31, 1996 (Box 14)
      - Letters: August 1, 1996 - October 15, 1996 (Box 14)
      - Letters: October 16, 1996 - December 23, 1996 (Box 14)
      - Letters: 10 January 1997 - 30 April 1997 (Box 14)
      - Letters: May 1, 1997 - July 31, 1997 (Box 14)
      - Letters: August 1, 1997 - December 31, 1997 (Box 14)
      - Letters: January 4, 1998 - March 31, 1998 (Box 14)
      - Letters: April 1, 1998 - August 27, 1998 (Box 14)
      - Letters: September 1, 1998 - December 31, 1998 (Box 15)
      - Letters: January 1, 1999 - March 31, 1999 (Box 15)
      - Letters: April 1, 1999 - June 30, 1999 (Box 15)
      - Letters: July 1, 1999 - September 30, 1999 (Box 15)
      - Letters: October 1, 1999 - December 31, 1999, 2 (Box 15)
      - Letters: January 3, 2000 - February 29, 2000 (Box 15)
      - Letters: March 2, 2000 - April 30, 2000 (Box 15)
      - Letters: May 1, 2000 - June 27, 2000 (Box 15)
      - Letters: July 1, 2000 - August 31, 2000 (Box 15)
      - Letters: September 1, 2000 - December 27, 2000 (Box 15)
      - Letters: January 1, 2001 - February 27, 2001 (Box 15)
      - Letters: March 1, 2001 - July 31, 2001 (Box 15)
      - Letters: August 1, 2001 - September 30, 2001 (Box 15)
      - Letters: October 1, 2001 - December 29, 2001 (Box 15)
      - Letters: January 2, 2002 - July 31, 2002 (Box 15)
      - Letters: August 5, 2002 - December 31, 2002 (Box 15)
      - Letters, 2003; 2 (Box 15)
      - Letters & email: August 1, 2003 - December 29, 2003, 2 (Box 16)
  - Writings and Other Papers
    - Writings (1988-1990) and "Samizdat" (1991), 1988-1991 (Box 16)
    - "The Advance on Mesmer", 1990 (Box 16)
    - "Chan", undated (Box 16)
    - "Further Apocrypha", 1991-2001, undated; 2 (Box 16)
    - "Further Apacrypha"; Chartings; The Ancient Use of Stone, undated (Box 16)
    - The Ancient Use of Stone, 1998, undated (Box 16)
    - "Rue de Tangier", 1991-1992; 2 (Box 16)
    - Newsletters, 1977-79, 1977-1979, undated (Box 16)
    - Provocations, 1991 (Box 16)
    - Hocquard, Emmanuel, translated by DiPalma and Valery, 1995, undated (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous poems, 2003 (Box 16)
    - "Aegyptian Ledger", undated (Box 16)
    - "Bumping into Wultzers", undated (Box 16)
    - "Nothing With the Sun", 2000 (Box 16)
    - "Indiscretions of the Minotaur," uncollected poems, 1968-1971 (Box 16)
    - "Touchmarks and Miscellaneous Poems", undated (Box 16)
    - "Five Works", 1988-1990 (Box 16)
    - "London, Summer", 1969 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous poems, 2003, undated; 2 (Box 16)
    - "Pages from a Work in Progress", undated (Box 16)
    - "Arcade", undated (Box 16)
    - "Pharaoh's House and the Inner Codes of an Enormous Past," early drafts, undated (Box 16)
    - "Reference Folly", undated (Box 16)
    - "Transcription", undated; 2 (Box 16)
    - Letters, corrected laser proofs, undated (Box 16)
    - Lettres, traduit de l'american par Vincent Dussol," first draft, 1999 (Box 16)
    - Letters, translations, 1999 (Box 17)
    - Letters, revisions, 1999 (Box 17)
    - Motion of the Cypher, 1995 (Box 17)
    - Provocations, 1994 (Box 17)
    - "Drafts and Fragments", 1997 September (Box 17)
    - Le Tombeau de Reverdy, undated (Box 17)
    - "Arcade", undated (Box 17)
    - "The Void", undated (Box 17)
    - "Ragolo", 1988, 2001 (Box 17)
    - "Across the Lens", 1997-1999 (Box 17)
    - "Jihadgraphy", 2002 (Box 17)
    - Poems, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Initial typed manuscript, undated (Box 17)
    - "Red Houe," MS, undated (Box 17)
    - "Further Apocrypha," MS, 1991-2001 (Box 17)
    - "Agora," MS, undated (Box 17)
    - "The Wick", "Ode", 45°, undated (Box 17)
    - "Pieces of the Part," MS, undated (Box 17)
    - "The Thirty-One," MS, undated (Box 17)
    - "Sgraffiti," MS, undated (Box 17)
    - Initial typed MS, undated (Box 17)
    - "Across the Lens: Writings 1997-99," MS, 1997-1999 (Box 17)
    - Between the Spaces, 1970 (Box 17)
    - "Event Horizon Writings, 1995 - 2000" (Box 17)
    - Initial typed MS, undated (Box 17)
    - Drafts for Metropolitan, 1986-1988; 2 (Box 17)
    - Notes for six poems, 1996 (Box 17)
    - "Event Horizon", "Blackbird Weather", and other writings, undated (Box 18)
    - "Nothing With the Sun," initial typed MS, undated (Box 18)
    - "Through the Motion," initial typed MS, undated (Box 18)
    - "Gnossienes," drafts, 2001; 2 (Box 18)
    - "Further Apocrypha", undated (Box 18)
    - Coridor Métropolitain, undated (Box 18)
    - "Babylon Shine Under the Damp Moon, etc.", undated (Box 18)
    - "The Adventures of Mesmer," MS, undated (Box 18)
    - Early MSS, 1968-1972; 2 (Box 18)
    - Platinum Replica, undated (Box 18)
    - Uncollected sequences, 1990-2001; 2 (Box 18)
    - Reckoning, 2002; 2 (Box 18)
    - The Ancient Use of Stone, undated (Box 18)
    - Homage, undated (Box 18)
    - Crystals II, 2000, undated (Box 18)
    - Corridor Métropolitan, translated by Vincent Dussol, undated (Box 18)
    - "Across the Lens", 1997-1999 (Box 18)
    - Untitled typescript, undated (Box 18)
    - "Indiscretions of the Minotaur", undated (Box 18)
    - Letters, undated (Box 18)
    - Palimpsest, 1995 (Box 18)
    - "The Thirty-One Sequels", undated (Box 18)
    - Moragh, undated (Box 18)
    - Letters, 1999; 2 (Box 18)
    - Provocations, 1994 (Box 18)
    - Between the Shapes, draft, 1966-1968 (Box 19)
    - Cuiva Sails, undated (Box 19)
    - Poems, drafts, 1978-1984; 2 (Box 19)
    - Initial typed MS, undated (Box 19)
    - "Hours", undated (Box 19)
    - "Territory", undated (Box 19)
    - Uncollected poems, 1968-1973 (Box 19)
    - "November", undated (Box 19)
    - "The Stone War Companion", undated (Box 19)
    - "Night", 1968 (Box 19)
    - Metropolitan Corridor, undated (Box 19)
    - "Max: A Sequel", undated (Box 19)
    - Corridor Métropolitain, 2000-2001 (Box 19)
    - The Jukebox of Memnon, undated (Box 19)
    - Initial typed MS, undated (Box 19)
    - Provocations, 1994 (Box 19)
    - "Pine Box", undated (Box 19)
    - "Palimpsest", 1995 (Box 19)
    - Letters, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 19)
    - "Rue de Tanger", 1991-1992 (Box 19)
    - "Agora", 1998 (Box 19)
    - Unidentified, 1997, undated; 2 (Box 19)
    - Motion of the Cypher, 1993, undated (Box 20)
    - Notes for six poems, undated (Box 20)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 20)
    - "Indiscretion of the Minotaur", undated (Box 20)
    - "Rue de Tanger", 1991 (Box 20)
    - "Pharaoh's House: The Inner Codes of an Enormous Past", undated (Box 20)
    - "Manoeuvre", 1977-1997, undated (Box 20)
    - "Three Sequences", undated (Box 20)
    - "Agora", 1998 (Box 20)
    - "The Bellaire Catastrophe", undated (Box 20)
    - Prose, 1998 (Box 20)
    - "Notes for Six Poems", "A Fabric", 1996-1997, undated (Box 20)
    - Unidentified, undated; 4 (Box 20)
    - Drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1997-2002, undated; 14 (Box 20)
    - The Ancient Use of Stone, 1998 (Box 20)
    - "Twenty Poems", 1999 (Box 20)
    - "Three Threads Five", "Pharoh's House", 1994, 1998 (Box 20)
    - "Sgraffiti", 1968-1971 (Box 20)
    - "Rodeo Radio", "Crystals", January Zero, undated (Box 20)
    - "Territory", undated (Box 20)
    - "Macaroons", undated (Box 20)
    - The Jukebox of Memmnon, undated; 1 (Box 20)
    - "Night", 1968 (Box 20)
    - "Arcade", 1998 (Box 21)
    - Unidentified manuscript drafts, 1988, undated (Box 21)
    - Hôtel des Ruines, undated (Box 21)
    - Selected poems, 1966-1986 (Box 21)
    - "Nervals", undated (Box 21)
    - "Hot Bird MFG" and letters, 1991-1997; 5 (Box 21)
    - The Ancient Use of Stone, 1990-2000 (Box 21)
    - "Further Apocrypha", undated (Box 21)
    - "Across the Lens: Writings, 1997-99", 1997-1999 (Box 21)
    - "Event Horizon: Writings, 1995-2003" (Box 21)
    - Unsorted typescripts, 1994-2001; 5 (Box 21)
    - Corridor Métropolitain, translated by Vincent Dussol, undated (Box 21)
    - Rigolo, typescript, 1988 (Box 21)
    - "Jihadography", 2002 (Box 21)
    - "Meditation in the City", 1998-2001 (Box 21)
    - Unsorted typescripts, 1990-2001; 3 (Box 21)
    - "Agore," first revision, undated (Box 21)
    - Jukebox of Memnon, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Provocations, proof, 1994 (Box 21)
    - Book proofs and miscellaneous material, Jukebox of Memnon, 1988 (Box 22)
    - Book proofs and miscellaneous material, "Cuive Sails", 1978 (Box 22)
    - "The Void," typescript, undated (Box 22)
    - "As Umbrellas Follow Rain," MS and revision, 2001 (Box 22)
    - "Minority Opinions in the Athens of Pericles", 2005 March (Box 22)
    - "Chrestomathies and Lecture Notes", undated (Box 22)
    - Drafts and notes, 1969-2005; 3 (Box 22)
    - Poems, typescript and autograph manuscript notes, 2005 May; 2 (Box 22)
    - Janvier Zéro, illustrated by Maya Anderson's students at the Ecole des Beaux Arts, Bordeaux, 1998 (Box 22)
    - Raik, page proofs, 1989; 2 (Box 22)
    - Raik, undated (Box 22)
    - Planh, first drafts and early revision, undated (Box 22)
    - Drafts of poems, undated (Box 22)
    - "Selected Poems: 1966-68," preliminary manuscript later titled " Numbers and Tempers: Selected Early Poems ", 1966-1986; 2 (Box 22)
    - Collected books, 1993-2001 (Box 22)
    - Notes, drafts of poems, 2004 November (Box 22)
    - "Poems 1965-", undated (Box 22)
    - "The Lion in the Maze", 1996 (Box 22)
    - The Ancient Use of Stone, 1998 (Box 22)
    - "Night Copy," typescript, 1972-1991, undated (Box 22)
    - Poems, drafts, 1977-1996, undated; 3 (Box 22)
    - Cuiva Sails, 1978 (Box 22)
    - Lettres, undated (Box 22)
    - Rodeo Radio: A Text for Jack Spicer, undated (Box 22)
    - Poems, drafts, 1990 (Box 22)
    - Drafts, undated (Box 22)
    - "Text and Occultation," drafts, 1989; 2 (Box 22)
    - The Poetry Project and other poetry organizations, 1980-1994, undated; 4 (Box 23)
    - Drawings for Numbers and Tempers, Elizabeth Dipalma, 1990 (Box 23)
    - Dipalma biography, 2003 (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous short writings, 1994, undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1975-1993, undated; 3 (Box 23)
    - Visual material, undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous material, undated (Box 23)
    - "Artwords & Bookworks", 1978 (Box 23)
    - "Further Apocrypha", undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous material, undated (Box 23)
    - Yale News article, 1996 November 13 (Box 23)
    - Chartings, undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous re: Janviero Zéro, undated (Box 23)
    - Unidentified photograph, undated (Box 23)
    - Tables, 1996-1997 (Box 23)
    - Visual material, 2000; 2 (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 2002-2003, undated (Box 23)
    - Newspapers, 1967-1970, undated (Box 23)
    - "Hot Bird MFG" and "Four Songs", 1993 (Box 23)
    - "Un Enchantement Final Suivi D'un Petit Cantique Improvisé" and "Le Tombeau de Reverdy", 1998, undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous visual material, undated (Box 23)
    - "Ximage," Betsy Brandfass, 1997 (Box 23)
    - "Lake of Dead Trees," miscellaneous film slides, negatives, and contacts, undated (Box 23)
    - Lettres, proofs, 2003 January 16 (Box 23)
    - "Photos by Elizabeth DiPalma", circa 1972 (Box 23)
    - "XX Else", undated (Box 23)
    - "Postage One Penny", undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982-1992, undated (Box 23)
    - Visual work by Robert Jacks, 1974-1979, undated (Box 23)
    - High school diploma, 1961 May 31 (Box 23)
    - Printed Matter catalogue, 1986 (Box 23)
    - "Image Bank", undated (Box 23)
    - "Poems & Drawings" and "Nezzar", 1993, 1996 (Box 23)
    - "Clown War", 1977 (Box 23)
    - "Some Directions to the Avant-Gardes", 1982 (Box 23)
    - "The Ampersand", 1990 (Box 23)
    - "Two Essays," Nick Piombino, 1992 (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous visual material, undated; 2 (Box 23)
    - "Transition", 1982 (Box 23)
    - Postcards by Ken Mikolowski, 1985 (Box 23)
    - Salt Lick Press, undated (Box 23)
  - Artists' Books
    - "Arx", 1996 (Box 24)
    - "Birdbirgh", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Blooz", 1991 April 19 (Box 24)
    - "Boxx", 1995 (Box 24)
    - "Calculated Risk", 2000 (Box 24)
    - "Chamber", 1996 (Box 24)
    - "Cixarziga", 1996 (Box 24)
    - Collages, 1991 (Box 24)
    - "Detail", 1991; 7 (Box 24)
    - "Coketown Dial", 1995 (Box 24)
    - "Dire Straits", 1991 April 18 (Box 24)
    - "Doft Mix", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Domain", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Eight Pyramids", 1977 (Box 24)
    - "Evidence", 1992 (Box 24)
    - "First Profile", 1991 April (Box 24)
    - "First World Whirl", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Focus", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "FX", 1991; 2 (Box 24)
    - "The Ghost of a Tin Can", 1991 (Box 24)
    - "In Harbor", 1991 (Box 24)
    - "Isles", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Jäger's Jag", 1991 April 19 (Box 24)
    - "Knock", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Landscapes", undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - "Lor'e", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Lumens", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "The Man With Two Shadows", 1996 (Box 24)
    - "Matak", 1976, undated; 3 (Box 24)
    - "Metrik (2)", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Moke", 1991 April 19 (Box 24)
    - "Newhizding", 1991 April 21 (Box 24)
    - "Outrageous Modesty", 1977, undated; 5 (Box 24)
    - "Outrider", undated (Box 24)
    - "Qua", 1992 (Box 24)
    - "Quadrant", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Realm", 2000 (Box 24)
    - "Safari", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Seven Poems (1967-68)", 1994 (Box 24)
    - "Seed Book", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Short Rant (With Buried Page)", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Sight", undated (Box 24)
    - "Some Cuts", undated (Box 24)
    - "Sphere", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Starkers", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "The Subtracted Sun", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Surface Tension", 1991 (Box 24)
    - "Sweetpowder", 1981 (Box 24)
    - "Tag book", undated (Box 24)
    - "Tagenbuch", 1996 (Box 24)
    - "There & Then", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "This Guys the Skys Disguise", undated (Box 24)
    - "Thoughts on Personae", undated (Box 24)
    - "Torque", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Tropiques", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Tzuuka", 1978, undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - "Un Autre Monde", 1992; 2 (Box 24)
    - "Variant", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Veil", 1993 (Box 24)
    - "Venus", undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - "Weight of the Pose", 1993 (Box 25)
    - "Wigwag", 1993 (Box 25)
    - "Wiler", 1993 (Box 25)
    - "Palm Works", 1993
    - Untitled, undated (Box 25)
    - "Zo", 1992; 2 (Box 25)
    - "Zoot's Torpor", 1995 (Box 25)